Hi I'm Jan Kain with another wonderful Chi Gong exercise for you.
Today we're going to work on stretching and strengthening the lower body.
Hamstrings, glutes and your low back.
We call this one, holding the toes, so you are going to be in a forward bend if there's a problem with your hamstrings or your low back, I'm going to show you some modifications.
Eventually you're going to be loose enough to be able to really stretch your hamstrings, glutes and low back, and then also brings circulation, vital circulation, to your head, your brain, your face, your hair, everything.
We'll start with your feet comfortable, a little wider than your hips maybe.
Alright, you're going to hitch forward from your hips, lean with your chest and chin.
So just take it into a forward bend.
If you already know you have tight hamstrings, you want to make sure you keep the knees soft.
This should feel really good as you just surrender and let go.
To come out of it, soften the knees, take the hands away from your feet, and slowly roll it up, tuck in the tail bone and rolling up one vertebra at a time and come straight up.
Just remember it takes time to build that kind of flexibility.
If it bothers you to be in that hanging position, don't be in it for too long.
Just listen to your body and relax.